PROFILE

Seeking a challenging position in Big data technologies to utilize my skills and abilities while being resourceful, innovative and flexible.

Overall 10+ years of experience in IT, and 6+ years of experience in big data Technologies. Experience working in Python, Spark and AWS.

CONTACT

PHONE:

+91 810 667 8327

+27 71 271 6727

Linked-In Profile:

www.linkedin.com/in/shashidataengineer-jnb

FMAIL:

Shashireddy40@gmail.com

PORTFOLIO

https://shashireddy40.github.io/mypag

CERTIFICATIONS

ISTQB-CTFL

Big Data Engineering with Hadoop and Spark from E&ICT, IIT Roorkee

PERSONAL PROFILE

Full Name:

PATOORI SHASHIDHAR REDDY

Date of Birth: 10th May 1990

Languages Known: English, Telugu and Hindi

ACHIEVEMENTS

Employee of the Quarter FY17

HOBBIES

Chess Cricket

Traveling

SHASHIDHAR REDDY (SHA-SHI)

Senior Data Engineer Remote (South Africa / India)

EDUCATION

Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University, Hyderabad, India

Bachelor of Technology in Aeronautical Engineering.

WORK EXPERIENCE



Senior Data Engineer | Cape town, South Africa | Remote Oct 2020-Present (2+ years)

eBlocks Software (Client OLDMUTUAL SA)

Data Engineer | Johannesburg, South Africa Oct 2019-May 2020. (8 months)



South Software Sonata Software

Big Data Engineer | Hyderabad, India January 2015-January 2019 (4 Years)

🕪 IrusInfotech Pvt Ltd, India

QA Analyst | Hyderabad, India June 2011-January 2015 (3+ years)

SKILLS

Languages:

Python, Scala

RDBMS:

Oracle SQL Server, Redshift

Big data Technologies:

- Apache Spark, NiFi
- Airflow
- Hadoop, Hive, Delta Lake
- Pandas, NumPy

Utilities/Tools:

Docker, Postman, VS code

Cloud Platforms:

AWS (S3, Redshift, EMR, EC2, SNS, SQS, Lambda, Athena)

MS-BI

SSIS(ETL)

DEPLOYMENT TOOLS

- Terraform
- **Jenkins**

PROJECT #1:

Title: Data Systems (EDW)
Partners: Tigo, Airtel and MTN
Location: Cape town, South Africa
Duration: October 2020 - Present

Tools Used: AWS, Spark, Python, SQL, Airflow

Team Size: 5

Role: Senior Data Engineer

Description:

JUMO is the market leading banking as a service platform, enabling real-time access to funds at the lowest possible operating cost.

Integrating into JUMO's platform enables our partners to offer loans, savings and a wide range of financial choices to a new group of customers.

The first ecosystem partnerships were established with Tigo, Airtel and MTN to bring short-term loan products to people and small businesses in Kenya, Zambia and Uganda.

Responsibilities:

- used various operators ETL pipelines that extract data from multiple sources, Transforming and stored in Delta Lake in optimized way
- Focus on simplified data models that represent business processes, operational excellence, systems & services resilience and efficiency, availability, maintainability, security.
- Building and handling successful designs, pipelines and development using Spark and AWS for large data processing systems
- build and manage workflows programmatically with Airflow
- Working in agile software-development methodology and utilizing technologies such as Jira, Git, Jenkins, Spinnaker
- Improvement of engineering processes (i.e., design reviews, build, operations, testing, release/deploy, monitoring etc.).

PROJECT #2:

Title: CBR-R (CONDUCT OF BUSINESS RETURN REPORT)

Client: OLDMUTUAL SA.
Location: Sandton, Johannesburg.
Duration: October 2019 to May 2020

Tools Used: Spark, Python, SQL

Team Size: 5

Role: Data Engineer

Description:

The Conduct of Business Return must be submitted to the Financial Services Board which is the Regulatory Authority for the CBR. The CBR is applicable to all Insurers carrying on either a Long-Term Insurance Business, or a Short-Term Insurance Business, or both. It calls for metrics on several aspects, dealing with the conduct of the insurer as it relates to policyholders. Policy numbers, new business, cancellations, surrenders, lapses, benefits, claims, complaints and commissions are the focus areas.

Responsibilities:

- Design, create, build & maintain data pipelines
- Handling, transforming & managing Data using Big Data Frameworks.
- Building complete infrastructure to ingest, transform & store data for further analysis & business requirement.
- Generating Reports for FSB (Financial Board of South Africa) Using Hadoop ecosystems.

PROJECT #3:

Title : TUI Travel Group

Brands : Thomson Airways, Amadeus System, British Airways.

Client : TUI UK, British Airways. Location : Hyderabad, India.

Duration : March 2015 to December 2018

Tools Used : Hadoop, Hive, Spark, Sqoop, Cloudera, Tableau

Team Size : 10

Role : Big Data Engineer.

Description:

TUI Group is a multinational travel and tourism company. It is the largest leisure, travel and tourism company in the world, and owns travel agencies, hotels, airlines, cruise ships and retail stores. TUI Travel Group have several UK-based tour operators Thomson Holidays and First Choice, by using this brands Passengers able to Book Flight tickets, Hotels and Holiday Packages with Cheapest Prices to Major European Countries

Responsibilities:

- Designing and implementing semi-structured data analytic platform leveraging Hadoop.
- Extensively used Hive/HQL or Hive queries to guery or search for a particular string in Hive tables in HDFS.
- Worked on analyzing Hadoop stack and different big data analytic tools including Pig, Hive, and Sqoop.
- Implemented Spark using Scala and Spark SQL for faster processing of data.
- Exported the analyzed data to the relational databases using Tableau for visualization and to generate reports for the BI team.

PROJECT #4:

Title : eCRS (electronic Credit Rating System)
Client : National Australia Bank, Australia.

Location : Hyderabad, India.

Duration : January 2013 to January 2015.

Tools used : Eclipse IDE, SQL Server, SoapUI, Postman

Team Size : 5

Role : Junior Data Analyst

Description:

eCRS is an online Credit Rating System that helps the bankers/employees of NAB to take a decision about issuing loans to their respective customers (organizations). There are several external factors involved in this project in order to drive the banker to take a proper decision against issuing the loans to their customers. It's a web application with different roles aligned with different privileges to access the system. The data from this system would be pushed down to another project called GDW. So, the data extraction is a crucial process in this project.

Responsibilities:

- Developed SQL queries with various data sources like JSON, Parquet.
- Exploring and analyzing data, performing Grouping, Aggregation and working with joints.
- Querying data using SQL operations.
- Responsible for test scripts generation, testing and validation.
- Have a good understanding of Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC), involved in various phases like Requirement gathering, Analysis/Design, Development and Testing. Also, knowledge in Test Driven Development (TDD) process.

PROJECT #5:

Title : Grocer-kart

Client : Idea Logistics, Hyderabad.

Location : Hyderabad, India

Duration : June 2011 to November 2012

Tools Used : Quality Center, QTEST, SQL Server 2008.

Team Size : 5

Role : QA Analyst

Description:

Grocer kart is an online shopping portal they do save on the infrastructure costs that we would otherwise have to incur if we had a physical store. Since at Grocer kart, the customer always comes first, we have decided to pass on our savings to you in terms of discounts on products. Customer will realize that most products are priced lesser than the MRP.

Responsibilities:

- Have a good understanding of Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC), involved in various phases like Requirement gathering, Analysis/Design, Development and Testing.
- Responsible for test scripts generation, testing and validation.
- Analyzing Functional Requirements, Gathering and managing the Test Data
- Effective test case writing and execution resulting in improved coverage
- Providing input/status updates regarding test progress/results
- Assist in the assessment and planning of test efforts required for new functions/features under development
- Designing Test cases using HP Quality Center and Executing Manually.
- Defect tracking, analyzing and bug reporting using QC.
- Defect and trend tracking, reporting, and analysis